

Vilma Recchiuti

Graphic/UX Designer

N13 London www.vilmare.com

email: vilmarehotmail.com

BUSINESS PROFILE

My work experience ranges from freelance to corporate business and start up companies in fields such as Finance, e-commerce, travel, art and social network. I am always keen to learn new approaches to technology tools and processes.

EXPERIENCE

2004 to Present Freelance Graphic Designer

Photo retouching, brochures,

logos, rollups,

website graphic elements,

html and css for pages layout.

musicians Duo Romanelli Allevi, Italy

Photocert, London

artist Naomi Tagini, Italy, USA

Inevo, Italy

Made in Italy Mall (e-commerce), Ca, USA

El remedio natural (e-commerce), Ca, USA

2007 to 2012 **Graphic Designer**

Graphic elements

(Illustrator, Photoshop and

Dreamweaver),

a tool to build avatars (Flash),

SEO for the pages.

loken (social network startup), California

Oct 2008 April 2009 Internship

I collaborated in projects about issues of interest in the local community: using video camera for in studio interviews,

in the making of a video about the risk of driving under the

effect of alchool and other tasks.

Public Cable Television Authority Huntington Beach, California

Venere Net SpA **Web Designer** (now Expedia) At www.venere.com, an European Aug 2002 Roma, Italy Travel Accommodation Search Engine, Aug 2003 I used to find the right solution gathering the hotel managers requisites, considering the users needs and the portal resourses; as a result I built different but personalized websites, each for every luxury hotel, villas, resorts, apartment all contained in the portal structure with its own criteria. Tools used Photoshop, Dreamweaver, Html, CSS. **Web Designer** Pf Network, a financial planner portal and Jun 1999 Pf Network S.r.l. (startup) search engine, a startup company and Dec 2001 Alba Adriatica, Italy an experiment for that time. A real gym for creativity and professional experience. Tools used: Dreamweaver, Flash, Photoshop and free hand drafts and drawings. Internship Collaboration in a specific research project University of L'Aquila, April 1994 Department of Microbiology about the impact of micro pollution on Sept 1994 L'Aquila, Italy monuments. Internship I was part of the Microbiological Quality Hoechst Pharmaceutical Oct 1993 Control Team, testing all the pharmaceutical L'Aquila, Italy Mar 1994 products before they got out the production lines into the market.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in

1993 **Biology** (program of 4 years plus 2 on original research thesis)

L'Aquila University, Italy

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

2017 2017 2016	(UX) User Experience Gestalt Psychology and Web Design Bootstrap	IDF (Interaction Design Foundation) online IDF online online
2009	(SEO) Search engine optimization	online
2008 2008 2007 2007 2007 2006 2006 2006 2005 2005	History of Graphic Design Digital film and video editing 3-D Computer Graphics Animation Painting Webpage design Dreamweaver Digital Photography Illustrator Color and Design: two-dimensional Art Photography Drawing Photoshop	OCC (Orange Coast Collage) California OCC California
2001 1998	Css Html	
1994	Professional qualification as a Biologist	University of L'Aquila, Italy

LANGUAGES

Italian English